Janelle M. Kwofie

College Freshman

San Diego State University

Skills

From all my employment experience the main skills I have picked up: Leadership, Organization, Communication, and Problem Solving. Most of my skills stem from jobs that require human interaction and communication; through that, I have learned how to apply myself differently and use a growth mindset.

Computer Science Language:

Java

• HackerRank Certified in Java(Basic)

 \mathbf{C}

• Taking College Classes and self-study

Experience

Work Experience

Clayman Institute for Research on Women and Gender - Intern

Stanford University, Palo Alto, California June 2018 - August 2018

Performed jobs to enhance the working environment and helped with the completion of a research paper. Additionally, I was given workshops to further my research skills in the social science field

Camp Galileo - Summer Intern and Team Leader

Belmont, California

June 2019 - August 2019

I was a Summer Intern at Camp Galileo. I performed various duties including ensuring that camp materials are ready for each day. I worked with campers on various projects. I was promoted to a team leader within a few weeks on the job and I was assigned to lead a team of kids. I created fun activities to help the kids to follow instructions. I worked with the kids on different activities

to keep them excited and engaged. The job taught me how to be accountable and organized.

District Office of Congresswoman Jackie Speier - Intern

San Mateo, California

January 2020 - March 2020

As an intern in the office, I assisted in picking up cases and performing other duties with constitutes.

Volunteer Experience

Fortifying Bridges

Carlmont High School

2017 - June 2020

I led a program that brought underrepresented students in my school together. The main objective of this program, called Fortifying Bridges, was to create a safe space for others to share their feelings. Over 12 student groups joined this program. As the President, I was responsible for outreaching to students. I learned a lot about communications and the power of messaging and language. The program is now a resource for many students.

Feminine Hygiene Report and Presentation

Carlmont High School

2018 - June 2020

I led an initiative to make feminine hygiene products available at my school. My main goal was to reinstate product dispensers in all restrooms. I carried out a survey and I put together a student committee to present the survey results to the school administration. As the leader, I helped to create a unifying message and a goal for the presentation. Through this initiative, I learned to outline a goal, how to compromise, and how to understand the limitations of my goals.

Governance Council

Carlmont High School

2018 - June 2020

I am a secretary for the Student's Governance Council. As a member, I actively contribute to the student community and to various students' identity groups. In my role as secretary, I record and communicate the main ideas of meetings and I am responsible for submitting meeting minutes to the council. This role has improved my presentation, communication, and writing skills. I have also learned to be mindful of my body language and tone of voice.

Black Student Union

Carlmont High School

2016 - June 2020

I am the president of the Black Student Union, BSU. As President, I communicate with the school administration, community leaders, and the student body. I have helped the club move toward civil service and to be pillars of kindness in our community. Through this role, I have become more aware of how I can use my power. As a community leader, I should always strive to help the community through my club. For example, we lead club gatherings, item donations, and assist other clubs as needed.

Students Offering Support

Carlmont High School

2019 - June 2020

Students Offering Support, SOS, is an organization that assists students from going through a crisis. In SOS, I helped conduct conflict mediation and I provided individual support to students going through a crisis. My role helped me to become more compassionate and understanding. SOS has helped me to be mindful and to treat others with kindness and respect.

Colorstack Sprout Fellowship

ColorStack

January 2021 - Present

A mentorship program and training program for Computer Science students of color.

PSL Digital Marketing Workshop

PSL

January 2021 - Present

Digital Marketing Training and Workshop.

Education

Carlmont High School

August 2016 - June 2020, Belmont, California

At Carlmont I led numerous social efforts to make the school more accepting and comfortable for everyone regardless of creed.

San Diego State University

Computer Science Major, Honors Minor

August 2020 - Present, San Diego State University, Currently taking classes online at home

Currently, pursuing a Computer Science degree.

Awards

Black History Month Essay Contest winner for San Mateo Library District

Student Offering Support Core Leader Certificate